PROFILE

I am Mike Buruchara, a seasoned web developer on a mission to transform your online dreams into reality. I am a professional Web developer with 1+ years of experience in web development and web security with proven ability to transform client ideas into beautiful, functional design solutions while upholding the highest standards of professionalism and service. My skills set are as follows:

Proficient:

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Python Django Framework Windows, Linux OS Office (MS Word, excel) Security Procedures

Intermediate:

SQL databases, JavaScript Crystal Reports &Documentation Data Backup and Recovery Data Analytics Tools: Tableau, AlterlYX.

Beginner:

React, PHP, NextJs, NodeJs Digital and Email marketing

Soft skills:

Good communication Positive learning attitude Excellent professionalism

CONTACT

PHONE: 0792960010

EMAIL:

burucharamike@amail.com

HOBBIES

Programming
Web Development
Web Security
Cooking
Reading
Travelling
Research
Athletics

MIKE BURUCHARA

WEB DEVELOPER

EDUCATION

Kibabii University

3rd September 2019 – 3rd March 2023 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science: Data Structures, Algorithms, Computer Networks, Web Development, Security, Python Programming, Machine Learning, Al, Database Systems, Operating Systems and Software Engineering.

Jomo Kenyatta University

June 2023 – September 2023

CCNA 1: Introduction to Networks, IP Services, Network Access, Security Fundamentals, Automation and Programmability, WANs, Network Troubleshooting.

WORK EXPERIENCE

JayTec, Technical Support

April 2021-August 2021

Troubleshooting and maintenance of computer systems and networks. I provided technical support to end-users and assisted with hardware and software installations.

Center Of ICT Integration, Teaching

January 2023-March 2023

Developed and maintained a company website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Implemented responsive design and optimized the website for search engines using SEO techniques.

ZaTech FreeLancer

September 2023–Date

Currently working a seasoned web developer on a mission to transform clients online dreams into reality.

SKILLS

